<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Your awesome title</title>
    <description>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.
</description>
    <link>http://example.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://example.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 22:20:19 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 22:20:19 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Test-driven specifications</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We write code for fun. But we also write code to solve a problem based 
on provided requirements. Behind every new feature, there is a 
requirement or specification that our code must met.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can we verify if our code is really meeting those specifications?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are several techniques to solve this. Companies usually have demo 
meetings with the people who created the specifications so that they can 
provide feedback and approve the solution. This demonstration is simply 
a bunch of assertions to validate that the new code works as intended.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if a new functionality is affecting an old feature that was already 
working? Do we need to call a new meeting again to verify the old feature? 
What do companies do about it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems that companies try to solve this by creating specialized teams 
for solving defects and running regression tests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nowadays many software teams are striving to improve this process by 
creating automated functional tests which are often included at the end 
of the code development phase or whenever a bug is found.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These automated tests describe the specifications of the system. 
They specify how the system should behave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem with this approach is that we end up having specifications 
defined in two different places. One from the business requirements 
provider and the other from the functional tests team. 
The specifications from these two places need often to be synchronized 
to avoid misunderstandings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Teams end up not knowing who is telling the truth. They don’t know 
whether the business requirements have the right specifications or if 
the functional tests do. They often agree on consider the production 
code as the source of truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wouldn’t it be better if we write the business requirements and 
automated tests at the same time? By doing this, we could avoid many 
problems and confusions about the specifications when adding a new 
feature to the system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also could write our code confidently and verify it any time to see 
if our solution is meeting the specifications. We wouldn’t have to wait 
at the end of the iteration to validate if we are doing the right thing 
or if we are impacting another feature that we shouldn’t be affecting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People who create and define business requirements are often not 
familiar with code writing. However, it wouldn’t be difficult to create 
a team that could translate those requirements into automated functional 
tests. Teams could even create tools to automate this task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Test-driven development specifies that we need to create a test before 
creating any production code. This sounds like we need to create the 
specification before creating the new functionality. There are new 
concepts like Behavior-driven development which propose to consider 
the specifications as a ubiquitous language and the use of tools to 
automate the specification verification process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We could take this further and provide specifications for every new 
piece of code we create. We could do this for each class and each method. 
Maybe someday we could stop consider tests as a QA tool and start 
consider them as a specifications definition strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2016 20:00:56 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://example.com/post/2016/06/20/tdspecs.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://example.com/post/2016/06/20/tdspecs.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>post</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
